hello everyone this is Frank defreitis
and welcome to another week of Hall talk
for the week of January 16th 2000 a
special broadcast this week it's the
first time that holotalk is being
broadcast both in the real audio format
and also in npeg format which has a
number of advantages because now you
have the portable MPEG players that you
can pick up at the electronics stores
and the stereo stores and you can
download MPEG files onto the MPEG player
and then take them whenever and wherever
you go to listen to the programming
instead of being attached to your
computer and they sort of work a little
bit well actually the opposite of a
digital camera work with a digital
camera you take a picture and download
that picture onto your computer with the
MPEG player you take the MPEG audio file
and upload it to the player then you
disconnect the player put it in your
pocket and go wherever you want to go
and listen to the file whenever you want
to listen to it so it's a little bit of
option here for a whole talk listers and
looking forward to hearing your feedback
on the new MPEG format as an option as
well to download the MPEG file if you
have a PC what you want to do is right
click on the link and then save the file
and if you have a Mac you need to option
click and then save the file once it's
saved to your computer you can then open
it in your MPEG player or of course
upload it to your portable MPEG player
as well
this week we have a little bit of a
different type of broadcast very similar
to a broadcast that we did earlier in
the year of last year when we did a
special Holo talk broadcast in Spanish
this one's going to be in French and we
have a teacher in the region here Debbie
Swann who's kind enough to come into the
studio and do some translation on an
introduction to holography a very simple
introduction for people in France who
may not be aware of holography how it
works or what it's about just enough to
just wet the appetite and we will take
this audio file in just a short amount
of time and put a special French web
page up very similar to the Spanish web
page that I have there now the only
difference is is we are going to have
the French audio recording in both real
audio and MPEG format but also this time
I'd like to put up several links to
different holography sites in France so
if any of the whole talk listeners out
there know of any
links to holography resources in France
whether it be companies or a holographic
artists or even amateur holography in
France could you send those links to me
and I will make sure that they are put
on the French Hollow talk page so that
anyone who comes on to hollow hollow
World itself they will see that there is
a special page for them in French and
they can go to that page and listen to
the broadcast being translated by Debbie
Swann and then have the list of
resources to holography Links in their
country on that page so if you have any
links could you please send them along
and I'll make sure that they're added to
the page and also if you're a science
educator and I know there are a lot of
you out there that listen to the program
at a high school or Junior High School
where foreign languages are taught you
may also want to mention this to your
foreign language French teachers as well
they could have their students come on
and see the webpage in French listen to
the French Hollow talk and also visit a
couple laser and holography websites in
France which would be a nice supplement
supplement to their education everyday
education in the classroom as well
okay before we get to that I have a few
announcements uh number one uh
holography night well actually it's
going to be holography day but for the
general public it'll be holography night
at Lakewood New Jersey on Monday evening
January 24th 2000 that's uh this
upcoming Monday night at Georgian Court
College I will have Holograms and on
exhibits specifically Holograms that
have been created using the new diode
lasers I'll be giving demonstrations of
how Holograms are made including using
the little shoebox holography system and
I also have a number of different lasers
here we will compare the helium neon
laser to these small diab lasers now
have one of the DS
[Music]
658-25 diode laser systems there as well
so if you'd like to come out we'd love
to meet you that's Monday night January
24th at Georgian Court College if you'd
like more information send an email to
me I know it's exit 91 off to Garden
State Parkway so it's an easy drive from
South Jersey or the Metropolitan New
York area I will send you more
information like the specific time which
you think you would think I would have
them locked down but I don't have that
marked down I had to find that out at
what time the nighttime presentation
will begin send me an email I'll give
you more information love to see you out
there also on May 6th at the Smithsonian
Washington DC I will be there throughout
the day from about 11 in the morning
till three or four in the afternoon also
given demonstrations on lasers and
holography and also have a small gallery
of excuse me holograms on exhibit at the
hershaw Museum so that'll be May 6th in
Washington DC at the Smithsonian we're
at the hershon Museum throughout the day
fun for the whole family so if you're in
the Washington DC area why don't you
come in and say hello and bring the
family with you there's going to be some
great Holograms there for all of you to
take a look at and on both of those
dates that we will have one or two men
members of the freelance group for
career and Workforce Innovation who will
finish out the program by letting you
know both the Monday night this upcoming
January 24th and also on May 6th on how
you can pursue careers in lasers and
holography and the photonics industry so
that will be a nice supplement to the
program as well to get some information
on resources on especially if you're a
student how you can pursue careers in
these different fields so I'm looking
forward to see you there if you can make
it out come up and say Hello I'd love to
meet you okay let's move on to the
special broadcast of the whole talk in
French once again I'd like to say thank
you to Debbie Swann who is kind enough
to come over and do the translations for
me and we hope to be able to continue
this trend of providing whole talk in a
number of different Native languages so
that we can really get an international
Flair at whole world for the field of
lasers and holography I believe it runs
about five minutes or so I hope you
enjoy it coming up next week we're going
to begin a series of broadcasts which
will run every week on West Coast
holographers so you want to tune into
that as well that'll be beginning next
week which will be actually January 24th
which will be the night I'll be in New
Jersey but I'll make sure I have that up
early on Sunday so that you access that
as well and don't forget that we have
the questionnaire on the initial hello
world page well each week you can give
your opinions and
have those opinions tabulated and see
the results right at hello world I'm not
going to come back on after the
program's over so I'll say thank you for
tuning in and hope you tune in each and
every week throughout the winter into
the spring this whole talk my engineers
and information and guests on the field
of lasers and holography take care see
you next week
hello this is Frankie Freitas and
welcome to a special broadcast of hollow
talk
I'm in the studio with a translator
Debbie swan
Museum
this is the second broadcast in a series
of broadcasts in a Disney and collection
being secretly that will bring Hollow
talk to other countries in their native
languages
let's start off by asking the question
what is holography
holography is very similar to
photography
photography except that when you look at
a hologram you see three dimensions
with a photograph you only have two
dimensions
for instance if you had a photograph of
an apple behind a box
you would not be able to look around the
box and see the Apple behind it
because the photograph has height and
width
but does not have depth
with a hologram you would be able to
move and look around the Box what
and see the Apple behind it
because the Hologram contains hype width
and depth
yes
let's examine what holography is used
for example
in science and technology holography is
used to test automobile engines
and aircraft tires among other things
if you have a credit card
you may have a hologram on that credit
card
example as well another example Catholic
studies which stops other people from
manufacturing cards
you may actually have a hologram on a
pair of jeans
so you know that when you buy the genes
they are made
who think they are made from them
in medicine Holograms are used to show
internal organs
and doctors can actually go up inside
and take measurements as if the organ
were really there hey
they need examples
in fine art artists use holography to
express themselves
the way traditional artists have used
oil and Canvas OR Stone uh
for example
Tableau they they can see okay
in commercial holography you may find a
hologram inside of a magazine
to be today
magazine which shows a three-dimensional
picture of the product
um
in the future you may have your favorite
television show projected right into
your living room
Holograms are created using lasers
it is only one of many uses of the laser
functions
other uses include Communications
when you make a long-distance telephone
call your voice travels over a laser
beam
[Music]
for example
foreign
recently we've discovered new ways to
make Holograms
using very inexpensive diode lasers
if you would like more information about
holography
I invite you to explore the whole world
website
um
this is Frank de Freitas
and Debbie Swan
thank you very much for tuning in
and enjoy your journey in learning about
lasers and holography